(305) 988-3494

Ruby Romeu — Full Stack Engineer

Yes, Ruby, like the programming language. Sattar is my Maiden name. I'm an engineer in the Greater Boston Area who has built multiple full-stack applications. Using software development as well as my background in education, my goal is to impact educational technology and the future of tech resources available in underserved communities.

Website rubysattar.github.io Github github.com/rubysattar Email rubysattar@gmail.com

SOFTWARE EXPERIENCE

General Assembly, Boston - Engineering Fellow JUNE 2020 - PRESENT

General Assembly is an immersive program that prepares software engineers with a holistic technical foundation essential for full-stack development.

- Built full-stack applications for teachers and currently conducting user research for continued iteration.
- Incorporated functionality from 3rd-party APIs to add complexity and nuance.

PROJECTS

OverAchiever — A flashcard learning application [Python, Django, React, Javascript, PostgreSQL, Bootstrap, SCSS]

The Holistic Educator — *A classroom connections tracking application* [Mongoose, Express, MongoDB, Javascript, Bootstrap, Handlebars, SCSS]

Education Donation Store— *E-Commerce Team project/application* [Mongoose, Express, ReactJS, Javascript, Bootstrap, SCSS]

OTHER PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

KIPP Academy, Boston - Lead Teacher FEBRUARY 2018 - JUNE 2020

KIPP is a mission-driven school where teachers regularly collaborate...

- Led a DEI workshop for a team of 30+ educators and school leaders, resulting in actionable commitments for the school environment
- Designed a K-8 Women's History curriculum, utilizing G-Suite tech resources.
- Led a class of 25 families, utilizing Tableau to analyze data and inform instruction

The Mildred (BPS), Boston - Lead Teacher OCTOBER 2017 - FEBRUARY 2018

Soldier's Field Park Children's Center of Harvard, Boston - *Lead Teacher* AUGUST 2015 - MAY 2017

TECHNOLOGIES

Javascript MongoDB

React NoSQL

jQuery Node.js

Mongoose Express.js

CSS/Sass Ruby

Bootstrap Django

SQL/NoSQL RESTful API's

SKILLS

Cross-industry technology

Teamwork

Leadership

Trouble-shooting

Communication

Coaching

EDUCATION

LinkedIn Learning -

Certificates

NOVEMBER 2019

HTML, CSS, SCRUM

Florida International University, Miami —

Bachelor's

MAY 2012 - DECEMBER 2014

Magna Cum Laude, Honors, 200+ hours of field research on ed-tech in school settings.